Sree Vadlamani

Manassas, VA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Sree-Vadlamani/3e1e6c055df89f8a

Analytics professional with experience in analyzing data, statistical modeling, and creating reports. Master's degree in Business Analytics and Project Management. Proficient in Microsoft Excel, SAS, SQL, Tableau, Statistical Analysis & Analytical Consulting

Please feel free to contact me at prakash.vadlamani@gmail.com

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist

ASAPDS - Remote - April 2017 to Present

- = Performed high level quantitative analysis on a variety of data sets, inspecting, cleaning, transforming, and modeling data to capture useful information and support decision making.
- = Extracted raw data from various databases, and prepared and analyzed data using Microsoft SQL server, Tableau, Excel and R.
- = Utilized quantitative analysis techniques including statistical machine learning, clustering, regression analysis, descriptive and inferential statistics to analyze large datasets.
- = Presented strategic insights and recommendations to senior management teams including C-level executives and developed workflow process in collaboration with multiple teams and departments.

Data Analyst

Tata Consultancy Services (TCS) - Hyderabad, Andhra Pradesh - June 2014 to December 2015

Marketing Analytics for customer targeting

A mid-sized retailer wanted to increase the percentage of customers who respond to the promotions and optimize costs

- = Generated hypothesis, analyzed the data and built models and created reports from the marketing and the sales data using statistical techniques and tools such as SAS, and Tableau
- = Researched and conducted a complete customer overview by segmentation and clustering using demographic, transactional, historical engagement, and campaign data to strategize the customer retention and client's investments
- = Achieved a 15% increase in the revenues per quarter which also improved the ROI for marketing with the help of customer segmentation and targeting as part of the new business strategy
- = Implemented the measurement plans to enable optimal utilization of resources which include A/B and multivariate testing

Marketing and Campaign Analysis

A mid-sized retailer wanted to retain existing customers and to grow and strengthen customer relationships simultaneously by cutting costs

- = Performed RFM analysis to increase the sales through promotional campaigns and marketing mix modeling using multiple regression techniques using the product, advertising and market outcome data
- = Assisted in formulating the promotional strategies by determining the effects of a promotion on a product by quantitatively evaluating the consequences of cannibalization, brand equity erosion, and forward-buying using Marketing Analytics.

- = Each model is run on a monthly basis to produce scores and statistical evaluations of customer behavior and product sales
- = Constantly measured and communicated progress against key business metrics by identifying drivers and recommended action plans for improvement to multi-channel marketing ROI
- = Responsible for generating and documenting updated reports and dashboards provide insights for decision making

EDUCATION

Master's in Business Analytics and Project Management

University of Connecticut School of Business - Hartford, CT January 2016 to December 2016

Bachelor of Technology in Mechanical Engineering

Acharya Nagarjuna University - Guntur, Andhra Pradesh September 2010 to June 2014

SKILLS

Financial Services, Marketing Analytics, Business Analysis, Data Mining, Predictive Modeling, Data Science, Tableau, SAS, Excel, SQL, Hadoop, microstrategy (1 year)

LINKS

http://www.linkedin.com/in/sreevadlamani

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- $= {\sf Tools: Advanced Excel, SQL, SAS-Base/JMP/Text\,miner/ETS\,(Time-Series), Weka, R, Tableau, Hadoop, MS\,Visio/PowerPoint}$
- Statistical skills: Linear/Logistic Regression, Hypothesis testing, Cluster Analysis, Random Forest, Cross Validation, Neural Nets, NLP Text mining, CART, Market basket Analysis, Naïve Bayes, Bootstrapping, Distributions
- = Analytical Skills: Time-Series forecasting, Survival Analysis, Recommender systems, Visualization, Conjoint Analysis, Optimization

CERTIFICATIONS: SAS Programming, Google Analytics, Data Journalism, R Programming, Statistical Learning